All right, we are gonna get going. Um,
time mismatch
presentation. So, I'm going to take you
through
during the course of this presentation
uh the theme that I had for uh my time
in DC this week uh presenting to Freedom
Tech. I enjoyed it. Uh made a lot of
friends there and I'm happy I went down.
Uh I'll talk about that. Of course, I've
got to talk about scary rates. Uh, I can
always tell when [laughter]
by by people reaching out and by reading
X what everyone's most scared of. It's
just amazing that uh it goes from oil to
rates to breath to everyone is just
every week there's a new thing. It's
just impossible to stay up with people's
anxiety. Don't know if that's a
reflection of not being able to make
money. Don't know if it's a reflection
of pressure. No idea. But we'll go
through that. Uh I will give you the
facts. So, for every person who tells
you every single time rates go higher,
there's a disaster. First of all, that's
a story that's not true. Um, second of
all, I'm going to take you through the
facts of the history of markets in terms
of myself building models of where the
contagion starts. I had to do this
because I grew up in Brazil and emerging
markets where if you didn't get out
before the things blew up, uh, you died.
And I watched many of traders and people
during the time of the 90s that were not
there. I did all of my theory on Jeffrey
Moore and economic leading indicators,
but then I'm also going to go into a
whole new mind. I've talked about this
book before. I think it's really
important for people to start thinking
about this. It's Muse time. Consumer
agents, the next AI moment. This is a
big one, guys. This is driving the
market today and I believe will be the
driver of the next 12 months. The
investments you make the next 12 months,
in my opinion, to be successful of
creating alpha will be about consumer
agents. Uh there's a bare market going
on within a bull market and I'm going to
go through that because I think this is
going to continue. Uh IWM over QQQ makes
new lows since the iPhone. Talk about
that and all the other good things
related to crypto. Oh, my disclosure.
Remember guys, I'm wrong.
Sometimes I'm wrong, sometimes I'm
right.
All right. So, yeah, I went down to DC.
I I really want to bring this up because
this presentation was about how there's
two different worlds that are going on
and you [clears throat] have a choice
and as you can see in my V up here you
can either be a linear thinker think
every time rates over the past whatever
amount of years have done XYZ this is
what's happened
or you can come over here and be in the
exponential and that's the problem. We
haven't had a rate rise while this has
been going on. We had a rate rise when
this was going on. Remember that as you
talk to people and I'll give you some
insights on how to avoid it. For the
people that were down in DC, the
community of people around Bitcoin, it
was a great event. I made some new
friends that I'll have for a long time.
You guys know who you are. And uh I
enjoyed the presentation. Hopefully I'll
be able to show it at some point. Uh but
this is really what the theme is about
on here. I wanted to show you guys the
notes that I put together just so that
when I was sitting down in the minutes
before I got up there and go on. So
there's human time. This is the system
that we're involved in. Um there's a
reason why housing and autos and retail
and restaurants and things are trading
where they should be at a bare market
level because rates are going higher. Uh
the ghost rails.
This is the other side of the equation.
So, you've got the human time where
everyone that's doing back tests based
on the linear world that no longer
exists. And most of them are above the
age of 50, which I will take you
through. Uh, the ghost rails is the most
important story. It connects back to the
agents. I'll talk about that, why it
matters. But here's the deal. The speed
of intelligence is changing. The speed
of money has to catch up. So, everyone
you're listening to
on the bank side, you got to start with
their age. I hate I hate to say that,
um, but it's just a fact. Uh there's a
big difference between someone who's in
their 50s and has already made money
telling you how the world's going to end
and someone in their 20s or 30s who's
working really hard at AI and
understands crypto. It's like two
different worlds and that's why there's
a time mismatch and people have not
adapted because they don't use AI. Um
Alvin Tooffler I referenced this book
but this is really what this is and if
you haven't heard of future shock you
should. We're at that point where
you will frighten and get everyone to
feel overwhelmed. And I think right now
anyone who's bearish honestly with
what's happening in AI,
they don't want to jump on board at this
point. Uh they can't. And I think
mentally they're angry at it. They think
it's a bubble. They think all these
things that fit in with anger. Um and I
think this makes sense because that's
what future shock is. If things are
changing too rapidly, then people don't
want the games to change. They don't
like managers making decisions based on
quantitative data. It's the old man in
the front yard routine. And I think
that's why I keep showing this, which is
I didn't want to be over here. I made
the journey over here in 2013, uh, my
trip to Silicon Valley and Singularity
University to make sure I didn't focus
on this anymore, believing that this was
no longer relevant. And that's what's
worked. And it's worked honestly since
2007. That's why IWM versus QQQ has gone
down every single year and it just
continues to make new lows. Even though
we had a rally and a broadening out in
the early part of the year, we're back
to the Mag 7 making new all-time highs
and the Mag 7 are gigantic and the
Russell 2000 2000 names are in trouble
because of AI. Uh not all of them. Some
of them make the infrastructure side as
we saw early. But when rates went higher
and oil went higher, these companies
don't have a way to survive. So this is
the world that we're in. And over here,
we're going to wean out a lot of people.
That's why I'm saying there's a bare
market with inside a bull market. So too
much of our life right now is polarized
into binary situations. It's a bubble.
It's not a bubble.
There's a time mismatch.
So, it's very hard for me to imagine
having been involved in markets for a
long time that Blockbuster earnings
bolster stocks record run.
And yet, while this is happening and
stocks are near their all-time highs, uh
I'm doing Julia's show uh soon. Um these
are just the three ones that picked up
on here. depression ahead. Michael
Pinto,
55 or higher. Uh Daniel D. Martino, I
don't want to disclose her age. I looked
up and go through it, but she's in the
bracket of me and the rest of Michael
Pinto and George Noble who's older than
us. All of us
above the age of 55 or above the age of
50. Let's just leave everyone else out
of this. Here's the main thing. You see
this chart? Does it look like it's going
higher? absolutely does to me. I mean,
this is a beautiful five waves up
consolidation, little triangle. It's
going higher. Do I think it's going
higher? I do. Would I bet on it's going
higher? No. I don't think it's worth the
time and the energy when I've got other
things to be involved in. Do I think
that this period here to compare to this
period is very different? Yeah, I do.
But again, everyone wants to just take
the story and get you scared because
this is going to go up to 10, 12, 14,
15. The government's got tons of debt.
All this stuff. It's a story. Here's
another story. I am 59 years old, soon
to be 60. This is what I did this week.
Crypto. Why now? All of the different
components. AI agents are the inflection
point. I'm showing you this because I'm
spending my time on where the world is
going, not where the world was.
Tokenization is happening. It's
happening now. I'm talking about how
tokenization will dramatically change
M2, will dramatically change monetary
economics today. This is the most
important thing happening in the world
today. And it's directly related to
crypto and it's directly related to AI
agents.
Bond yields, believe it or not, I did a
back test. There was no tokenization
during the 70s, 80s, 90s, and 2000s.
There was no AI in everyone's hands
accelerating at the pace, solving math
problems, stuff. None of that was there.
So, is it different? It's absolutely
different. I don't even know how people
don't see it. So, a whole new mind. Why
rightrainers will rule the world is
something I included in there. I'm going
to go back to it. This has been going on
for some time. I didn't just make this
up here. Remember when we were everyone
was telling us in 2022 when rates were
going higher and the Fed raised rates
how we were absolutely going to have a
problem?
We did have Silicon Valley Bank go
under, but it didn't even make a hiccup
on the market. We had a an inverted
yield curve, 100% probability of getting
a recession. We had this the lei
year-over-year, something I studied for
years, and yet I didn't fall for the
trap of it because I knew that this was
created during a time that didn't matter
anymore. Same thing with rates. Yes,
rates mattered in the past when
companies took debt out that didn't have
good balance sheets and they were
betting on the future. When people
bought houses, nobody buys a house now.
Housing is trading near all-time lows in
terms of sales. Everyone has positive
owner's equity in their home. It's a
completely different world. The
government is the one saddled with the
debt. So, if you want to bet that the
United States government's going to
default, as I wrote in that paper, blah
blah blah. I've heard this too many
times over the course of my life in this
business about how governments aren't
going to be able to get through having
debt. The LEI just went positive. We
never got a recession. But guess what?
Every other time that it was down there,
every other time we got a recession. So
that's why I'm saying there's plenty of
instances where this time is different,
but I want to give you stuff as facts
that if this I'll change my mind. If
year-over-year S&P goes negative, I'll
change my mind. And like I've said, I
got a recession signal here in the end
of 2007 near the peak. It was before the
peak of the market. It was right at the
peak of the market. When you have an
economy that matters, stock prices
reflect profits. They reflect hiring.
They reflect profit margins. All of that
stuff matters to whether rates are
having an impact. If rates are having an
impact and you're saying, "Well, there's
a bubble because stocks aren't going
down." Okay, but what about earnings
going higher? What about profit margins
going higher? I'll go through other
things as well. In 2000, before we got
into the recession, you got a sell
signal. The second derivative matters.
The second derivative tells you if
there's issues happening in the economy.
We are up 17% year-over-year, guys. Here
is credit spreads. This is taking the
Moody's BA yield relative to 10-year
yields.
I I'm sorry. When we have problems like
in 2000, spreads are widening. Spreads
are widening. They're always So, if
rates are going to have an impact,
you're going to see it in credit
spreads. It's not there. Jobless claims
for everything with the jobs market.
If companies are in trouble, if we're
going to have a problem in the market,
if rates are mattering, you're going to
fire people and they won't be able to
get rehired. They will go for
unemployment insurance. That's why this
thing matters so much before every
crisis.
Jobless claims are going higher. They're
not budging. So, when those things
change, I'll worry about it. Profit
margins, like I said, they're mean
reverting. They tend to go down before.
Look, they peaked in ' 07. They were
already declining. They haven't even
stopped going higher in a parabolic
fashion yet. And oh, by the way, this is
another fact. So everything I'm showing
you are facts. These are not a story I'm
putting together as a story. But people
using rates as the story, there's no
facts to it. It's just a story. Here is
the story or the facts.
Money supply or money market funds again
on a three-month base, they went higher.
Now, I don't care if this is
cherrypicking three months. What I'm
saying is that historically this is
happening in times not while the stock
market is sitting their all-time highs.
It's it's happening during panics.
There's flush with cash out there.
It's moving in because rates are higher
and people are collecting 5% 4% whatever
they want. So I've referenced this book
twice already in this in this uh video.
This was a very important book of my
life. I think I read it just before the
great financial crisis. This really got
why right ber why right brainers will
rule the world. This was written by
Daniel Pink who predicted that because
of technology and exponential
technology. This is just after the.com
bubble but knowing what was coming.
The world was no longer going to be
about mathematicians. It wasn't going to
be. This is what I always say about
Michael Bur. Everyone who made money on
the housing market. Look how long it
took before that had an impact to go
through. But regardless, you can't bet
on the technology side to go through it.
This is a different world. We're in a
completely different world. So to say
this time isn't different isn't that is
an old man on the front yard story. It
is different.
The demographics, this is a fact,
Claude, who uses it?
Those people I mentioned, meaning myself
and anyone above the age of 55, who are
the people normally interviewed on
podcasts as macroexperts,
we're interviewed. Our bracket of age is
55 to 64. 2.2% of us use AI. How can you
have a view on today's economy and on
today's market if you don't use AI? I
don't think it's possible because here's
where we are. It's about to get worse.
So, in 2022 is when Chat GBT came out.
Here we are now in 2026. So, unless
people are using it on a regular basis,
of which, if you're impressed with the
images, and everything I put together in
this video, it's all done via AI. I
learn everything through AI. I have Muse
doing all of my checks, my bank fraud
alerts, everything like that is done
with AI. Anything that comes out new,
I'm working on Jev now, and I'll show
you that in a little bit. Anything
that's new I'm trying to give you guys,
but I'm also trying to use it myself for
what's going on. This is what's coming.
Robots, science and technology,
flying cars, Mars. Is this time
different? Of course it is. Now, here's
where we are. The personal agent. It's
finally arrived. This is a big deal.
This is a major thing. This was the
number one thing of the market this
week. New York Times, not the most
positive uh paper on technology. I gave
my life over to Meta's AI agent and I
was blown away. So was I.
Here's mine. Yubie. For all you Nick
fans, Yubie Brown was my favorite coach.
That's in honor of Hubie. So, I named my
He looks like a Yubie. Uh, this is just
my fraud alert. See, someone tested
something. AI is all over the place. I
asked it to go back and see if it saw
any charges the prior week. Uh, the
downloads are surging. This is what came
up the other day for someone who tried
to get who showed me. Here's the
partnership with PayPal, Expedia,
Shopify, Instacart,
Meta Stock was up 14% on Monday.
It drove Intel, AMD, but also the other
Mag 7 because guess what they have too?
They're going to benefit from this,
especially when I take you through why
it happened. So remember back in July
July 2nd meta Mark Zuckerberg I covered
this just said at an internal town hall
meeting that AI development over the
last four months hasn't accelerated in
the way we expected. Think about that
and now look here. So I went in to AI
and I basically said I want you to go in
and find out what changed from that time
because it seems to be able to get from
there and all of a sudden be able to
launch this product. What happened? and
I asked it to go into Reddit into X into
all employees of Meta and get whatever
information you can get other than
what's been out there as well and then
put it together. So basically you can
see on the chain of events they release
1.1 then 3 weeks later was 1.2 then 3
weeks later was 1.3 and all of a sudden
you have the Muse consumer launch.
Clearly as you go through this things
were changing and the benchmark move was
happening. And the reason this is
important is when you go through it and
you read what they said changed, we're
at the point of effectively recursive
self-improvement or at least the models
are so smart that their ability to
contribute to them getting better is
increasing dramatically. And this is
where when you go through it and you
have to think about this because this
means the competition for consumer
agents is coming quickly and the models
are just going to get better and better.
And that's what this was about. So again
this is from Leopold Ashen Brener's page
71 of situational awareness and when we
hit this point which as I've mentioned
his expectation with this would be 2027
and based on what Zuckerberg said in
June or in July two months later
everything changes. Go back to Andre
Karpathy who on Dwarash in October of
last year said agents would be a decade
away. constantly everyone with inside
the space is underestimating how fast
this is moving.
Remember it wasn't too long we were
talking about the pause. No pause. So
this week Opus 5.5 released. You
probably even see lower prices fable
level performance. Then GPT6 Soul and
Luna came out. Lower cost, fewer
mistakes. Wasn't just those. Google
released one. A uh ch China released a
bunch. Forget it. We are this week. The
model fire hose is wide open. Recursive
self-improvement.
And so what's coming?
A new kind of AI model from chatbt
inventors. Thrilling developers.
So Jev came out. I'm I'm not going to
spend a lot of time on Jev at this
point, but I am going to let you know.
You have to go read what this is doing
because this is very different than an
LLM. So this is not another one
competing with ChateBT. And this this is
actually one that you would use with it.
And that's what I'm working on because
with the treasure hunt and again for
those of you who had your children do
this on my uh the on on my video and and
the subscribers, Jev is now the next
thing for them to play around with. Jev
analyzes everything. So it's not just
something that's going to go back as an
LLM and do a back test. This one is
making decisions based on everything. it
is completely different. So the it
becomes a decision engine. So I'm
working on this to kind of go through it
and bring the agentic trading and show
you guys what I'm doing in it. But
again, all of this just says that we're
right here. So now that the agent has
arrived
Muse,
what happens Microsoft? So now all of a
sudden the Mag 7 and I want to since
people reach out and go, does this mean
you're not negative the the
hyperscalers? Does this mean you're not
negative SAS completely?
I don't know how many times to like go
through this. My viewpoint on everything
is that the infrastructure compute names
will outperform. So my thematic
portfolio on the Agentic infrastructure
is up 46% through Friday. The Mag 7 are
up 10%. Salesforce.com despite this
major rally is down 10% year-to date.
There will be periods where all of them
will outperform, but in the end, I think
they'll all run into trouble. And what
these guys will run into, they're going
to get benefits, but they're going to
have competition from each other and
competition from OpenAI and competition
from Anthropic. They are going to drive
prices lower. And so, there will be
periods where the enthusiasm and the
hope will get there, but in the end, I
believe all of them will go through
multiple compression. And remember, the
Micron has already gone through multiple
compression to very low levels. I know
the mag seven have it. I know software
has as well. They're all going to go
through it. That is the bare market with
inside a bull market. And that, my
friends, is what happens normally when
rates go higher is we get multiple
compression. Where was the S&P 500 PE
back in 1980? Go back and look at your
books. It wasn't 20, it was below 10. I
believe and we'll say it publicly that
based on my viewpoint of the competition
from tokenization, the competition from
AI and the fact that I don't see rates
for the near-term coming down
dramatically. I think the pressure on
all of these companies is actually going
to come from the deflationary side. And
that deflationary side is going to come
from tokenization, expanding the amount
of things to invest in at the same time
as AI making things cheaper and cheaper
and just driving competition to hyper
competition. Apple, Siri getting closer.
I'm sure now because of how good the
models are, we're finally going to get
that. Amazon. Why do you think Amazon
has a standoff over Muse? I think again
we're at the point of competition
for me. Check it out.
>> Well, you guys got to hear my uh my iPad
jumping into the equation as I said her
name. Uh met a standoff with Amazon.
Could be a sign of things to come. It's
always good when you're one man. John,
I'm not editing this out, so I hope you
enjoyed that. Um had the opposite effect
on some financial services. online
travels. We're in another stage where I
think people are trying to figure out
who loses and who wins from the agents.
I think this is going to be a big deal.
And remember, OpenAI is going to release
their agent. So, you're starting to get
more
response uh to Meta's Muse. There's
going to be a lot of them. So, let's go
back to something I've shown you guys
relentlessly this year in terms of the
infrastructure and compute needs.
They're insatiable.
We had enterprise agents. we didn't have
consumer agents. So, we already had the
enterprise. This was in the first half
of 26. So, let's assume now we're here.
Consumer agents are just starting and I
would expect that they're going to
explode in terms of usage just based on
the downloads. So, here's one of the
slides and the most important thing for
you guys to think about. You can choose
what side you're on. This is the way the
economy is right now. So, think of this
as the mag 7 in technology. Over 50% of
the S&P 500 is over here. Over here are
homebuilders and auto companies like
Ford and all this stuff
that the young kids don't care about and
that the people above the age of 50
think is what drives the economy. This
is what drives the economy. It's in the
market cap. We know that the Russell
2000, these companies that still need
debt, that care about rates, they're not
going to make it through this. This is
the bare market within the bull market.
So you can either focus on the bare
market signals or you can focus on the
bull market signals. This is the two
worlds that are going on and this is the
time mismatch. When I was in DC, I
talked about the friction. Anything that
has friction which will eventually get
the big mega companies as well on tech
uh eventually. What is going to happen
is that more and more young people are
coming over here. The AI native
companies are rising over here. All of
this stuff is going to disappear
slowly.
But it's going to happen. So again, the
future began begins belongs to a
different kind of person.
So here you go. Here's the scary chart.
Here's the oil chart. Oil is the same
price as it was in 2007 despite the fact
that disposable income and everything is
through the roof. This is what's scaring
you. Those two things. I showed you
facts about the economy and I showed you
facts about agents and the acceleration
of AI. Those are facts. Those are not
guesses. So there's a bare market within
a bull market. Lowers the barriers to
entry. AI reduces the cost to start and
compute. Faster innovation cycles. Most
erode more quickly. Margin pressure.
Shorter duration. Multiple compress. So
multiples compress is the bare market.
We have the most important technology
ever. People compare this to the dot
bubble when Cisco was trading at 100 PE
and Nvidia is trading at 15 next year's
earnings. This is not a bubble. This is
the opposite. This is a bare market
where we are pricing in that AI's
competition will destroy the value of
anything outside of five years. And that
is going to get shorter and shorter. So
as they're making money, they're
starting to say what actually happens.
So before AI, 10 bucks a share. After
AI, think salesforce.com. But now the
multiple goes from 30 to 10. The stock
price goes down. Again, this is what's
happening in the market. And what you
need to be focused on in terms of
investing is smaller businesses, AI
native companies, the infrastructure
side, the intellectual property. We're
going to have a change because more
asset classes are coming and they're
coming through tokenization. So, public
equities dominated. It's going to get
brought up, broken up into a bunch of
things. And if you don't believe this,
that's what my job is with the crypto
side. And so for those of you who have
ignored crypto, you know, tokenization
is coming. You don't, you're reaching
out more and more. I got more people
coming to me on this. This is really
important because tokenization plus AI
is a gamecher for the economy. And
that's why we have a bull a bare market
within a bull market.
The groups that are not part of this are
going to suffer. And what rates are
meant to do is to go high to drive them
out of business because AI is driving
rates higher because nominal GDP is
driven by AI. So the winners are moving
rates higher. They are forcing out the
people that can't survive. The companies
that can't survive with rates at higher
levels. So the businesses that will have
to replace them will be the ones that
can survive on that. The only way you
can do that is not have debt today.
Start your business now. Use humanoids.
Use AI. That's what's coming for
housing. All of it. House prices will
come down eventually. They'll come down
when the cost of building them goes
down. That'll be in five years
beginning. You have to start thinking
this way because that's the way this
goes. Rates are a way to get rid of the
weak and that's what's going to happen.
Breath. I like Jason's work. He's been I
think reluctant because I I think in the
back of his mind he's like I I don't
even know. We've never seen breath this
bearish in the last hundred years. Okay,
this is the reason why
um IWM [clears throat]
relative
to QQQs is the white line. The orange
line is the breath
they're tracking. It makes sense that if
you have companies worth 30 trillion
and a bunch of stocks that combined are
worth 4 trillion.
H
it's a different world, guys. It's a
different world.
This has been the widowmaker trade
making new lows. See that September
24th, new lows. IWM verse Q. This is not
a new thing. You know when breath was
really bad? when Amazon was beating
every retailer, that's when Breath was
bad, too. Breath is always bad during
these times when the Mag 7 do well. So,
here's that bridge to cross over to the
new side. This is where we start to get
in the interesting stuff. If you guys
haven't seen the Muse character, here it
is. So, what Yubie is doing, my Ubie, is
he's guiding people that want to go
learn new stuff. He's trying to help
them cross the bridge. He's the agent.
AI agents are really the thing that are
going to fix because I've learned that
humans don't adopt technology anytime in
history fast. That is the reason why we
have things like the.com bubble. They
get excited about it. They overbuild it
before it's ready. The AI agents are the
app store. The AI agents are the iPhone.
That's what it is for me. This is the
change. This is where tokenization,
crypto, and AI connect. That is the
bridge here. So that bridge is really
the thing that I'm measuring both in my
AI infrastructure basket for those of
you who saw my crypto video this week
and our subscribers. You're going to get
an education for all the mutual funds,
the macro people, the hedge funds that
are out there, even if you don't have
the ability to invest in crypto. You
need to understand the entire ecosystem
because it matters for public companies
because they will be disrupted. So this
is going to be a weird one. Everyone
focused on Amazon. They focused on
Ozmpic. When Ozmpic came all the re you
need to get the disruption names because
when the disruption comes the alpha's on
the short side. That's what this new
world is. The new world destroys old
businesses. This is more about the
companies to be short. If you go through
and look at how what percentage of
companies have outperformed the S&P 500
over the last one years, three years, 5
years, 10 years, it is a destruction.
There's just nobody outperforming. Part
of that is because of the market cap,
but part of that is because these small
companies are so tiny that you need some
kind of a cyclical recovery. We had it.
The PMIs went higher and now we're
making new lows in cues. That is not
supposed to happen. That's because rates
are going higher and they're suffering,
the majority of them. Here's
Salesforce.com.
The amount of people said, "Yeah, but
it's rallying. It's rallying. It's down
10% year to date. Now it's in a
downtrend again. the last five years
it's unchanged. Actually, it's down 15%.
Like, don't give me this garbage with
Salesforce.com.
Here's Visa.
Here's the name that gets brought up to
me the most. Visa and Mastercard. Unless
I'm missing something on the sentiment
side, guys. This is just going to be a a
knife fight for the P with as the PE
comes down because no one wants to give
into this. They just don't see how
crypto is going to do it. This was name
was brought up to me about eight times
this week. So again, I believe that
there will be no consumers. The
consumers will be Muse. If you haven't
got Muse, you can't even have a say in
it because you haven't used it. Muse
will change everything. And yes, I've
given it all my credit cards. I've given
it all my bank accounts, everything
about it. It already did information for
me. It did DMV work for me. It canceled
the Verizon FiOS thing because I saw it
on X and I went, "Oh, this is great. I
need to cancel something on there or two
and renegotiate." All of those things
you're going to be able to do. All
right. Now stocks really bearish chart.
S&P is about to make new all-time highs
and it's been consolidating after pole
consolidation. Pole consolidation
pole consolidation. This is cues.
IWM downtrend still above the 200 day
still pointed upwards. All that needs to
happen for this to go higher is what?
Oil just needs to come down. If oil
doesn't come down, it'll probably just
hang in here and be dragged around. But
this is not like some collapse or some
bad thing. It's just they suck with
rates. It's just a fact. Uh if you want
the one place that the bears can kind of
look and be like, "All right, let's see
if there's contagion." Now again, this
is one thing that hasn't meant anything
in terms of the last three years. But
let's just look bond went up. So the
long end has got to the point where for
some reason people are reaching for
volatility and fixed income which
usually means someone's getting hurt. So
I overlaid it with the OA OAS
for high yield.
It's barely budged but at least it's
moving. So for people want to be bearish
this is where I'd focus my attention.
You have the dollar rallying too. You
know you're getting a little bit of
deleveraging stuff. Everyone's freaked
out in gold and silver and things like
that. But the reality is credit needs to
widen out. This is the long-term chart
of OAS. Um,
okay. Just a reminder because I got
called or emails on the weekend. Are you
worried about and I can't believe this
guy even gets anything as like something
to follow? But AI stocks will drop 10%
on Monday morning. Brace for impacts.
All because of the pause trade. So, we
all know that that was a bad time to
sell stocks because they all gapped
lower because everyone was scared and
the knee-jerk happened and then that was
the low. So, I don't know how many times
everyone's going to fall for AI bear
stuff, bubble stuff. What does this
mean? It happens the entire time. And
remember, this was the end of
situational awareness. This is the area
where I was doing my midcycle slowdown.
And I'm I this chart is great. And more
importantly, the structure of what's
going on is really good. And the fact
that it's starting to handle bad news
really well when people are panicking.
Uh and oh, by the way, it was the best
week since the week after it. So, I
think the infrastructure trade has a
catalyst. I think that is the
recognition that the consumer agent
stuff is going to drive not only numbers
now, but people are going to start
talking in their numbers about how big
of an impact the consumer agents are
because the token numbers are going to
go up significantly. And that's the
reason why you've seen Intel, AMD,
you've seen names get hit on the other
side related to the disconnect. Now,
I haven't shown this in a while. We're
getting some good Brett. We got the
highest number of names above the 20-day
since back here. But most importantly,
when we were doing this here, as I said,
the ATR was very, very high. And now the
ATR is very, very good. I think we're at
the beginning, and I think these things
are going to get back to the highs.
meaning my agentic portfolio. Go pick
your names in it. Uh whatever the case,
I've told you the ones that I still have
decent sized positions on. Uh I've been
moving out of some of the tinier ones
and moving all of that in the crypto
because I believe crypto is the major
story on the back of the agent trade. Uh
a good video to watch uh is just
Blackston's John Gray. He I watched this
this week. It's really I I like read I
like watching uh people like John Gray
talk about what he's seeing in his
companies. He's got a bunch of private
companies. He gives a lot of numbers in
here related to how much they're using
AI. I'm not going to go through the
whole thing, but he does a really good
job. First of all, it's interesting. He
shows the explosive spending that has
happened uh from September of last year
to September of this year. 21% increase
on his companies in terms of their
spending. uh the payoff is already
showing up. He goes through the ROIC and
more importantly he cites all of the
places that it's happening. Lease
processing, code repair, like everyone's
worried about the revenues. They're
already happening. Absolutely. But
there's no way to measure where they're
happening. You know how you measure it
in profit margins. That's what this is.
They're show he breaks it down for you.
So it's showing up in productivity,
showing up in margins, earnings, jobs,
science. The limiting factor is now the
physical world. It's what we talk about.
That's why you invest in the physical
world. The biggest investment risk is
underestimating disruption, but
overpaying is also dangerous. So, as
he's going through this, he's just
talking about the things people have to
worry about, which again, cyber risk,
regulation, geopolitical tension. He
gives you both sides. So, I just think
it's important because he does a really
good job of basically going through
everything. I think the underestimating
disruption is why these companies are
going to have a hard time with their
multiples. I [clears throat] think all
companies that are big are targets and
that's basically what it comes down to.
I think friction is in companies. I
think AI native businesses that are
small are just not targets for the stuff
that's going to go on. So I think you
have to be on top and again companies
that don't have AI don't have the
protection, they're going to be an
issue, but people that do will be fine.
So the real returns he goes through it
like I said I think for people that
doubt what's happening he gives specific
examples of companies he goes through
this it is absolutely worth watching
again we're here so you need to stay on
top of this stuff
this was a great interview for anyone
who's seriously worried about hugging
face in the agent swarms brown who's a
lead openai researcher and Darkashh and
Dwar is a super smart guy who
understands this stuff inside and out
and most importantly as an interviewer
he attacks. I mean he he forces people
into a corner to go through it. This is
where you want open AI. They were the
ones that had the hugging face incident.
They were the ones that everyone read
about. Dwaresh is a good interviewer and
so this isn't on 60 minutes and this is
fairly complex but there's a bunch of
important points for people who are
worried about the swarms without
thinking about the positives that are
coming out of this. So again, he
explains multi- aent systems. I think
this is important. I think it's
important to understand what's been
happening with Navier Stokes, why that's
going on, what's been happening with
Muse, why that's happening. You have to
listen to what agents are able to do.
Most importantly, he does go through the
hugging face incident.
He goes through all of it. I don't see
how you can't leave that. And if you do
leave it being completely worried, then
you're not paying attention to this
part.
One of the major takeaways from the
incident, this is a quote from him, is
that people underestimated the AI. And
we never want to be in a situation again
where we underestimate the AI. It's a
weird world that because AI progress is
so fast, people are consistently
underestimating AI. The critical thing
here is that the reason this happened is
because people, humans, underestimated
it. So for everyone who's worried that
these things are just going to go out
there and go do what they need to do, is
it possible? Of course. But they're
talking about why we had this situation.
Just like when Mark Zuckerberg
underestimated AI, this is a really
critical point because that's why the
pause was so important. We are going to
be spending time on the best models,
either not releasing them or making sure
that the guardrails are different. He
goes into that in there. You should be
more happy with this kind of stuff.
Claude has discovered a previously
unknown enzyme system hidden in DNA of
of what will effectively be a structure
that looks similar to crisper. Now, I'm
sure you guys know gene editing and
crisper like stuff. So, if you go read
on X and or if you go read somewhere,
you will find people that say this is
nothing. You will find people that say
it's something. I want you again to just
focus on the fact that gene editing and
the advancements we're making on this
kind of science are unbelievable because
this is not an old technology. I
actually read this book or I I did books
on tape for it uh at high speed because
I was interested in what went on with
this with Jennifer I think her name is
Dana and I like Walter Isacson. I love
Da Vinci and I love Steve Jobs. The
reason I bring this up is Fangg Zang,
for those of you who read it, was in the
book as the major competitor to Jen
Jennifer. Um, he came out and he's the
only one I care about. I don't care
about a random biologist saying it's
good or bad. What I care about is
someone who is known and renowned for
his work and basically talking about how
science is changing in front of our
eyes.
And that is where we are is that when
did they set this up? They didn't even
set their biology research group up
until 20 until spring June 30 they
launched this. Again, this just
highlights that we're where we are in
the Leopold map. We are going to have
breakthroughs that are going to solve
things and that's why Fang Zang's part
of this is really important as going
through it. McKenzie new research out
emerging trends in AI enabled drug
discovery suggest accelerated discovery
cycle time. So again we're getting this
whole thing and silicico medicine is on
here twice. I've talked about their
relationship with Eli Liy. You guys can
go through all this stuff on your own.
The only reason I'm going through this
is because I believe that healthc care
and uh and drug pharmaceuticals will be
a major part of the agentic side. So AI
consumer agents are going to get people
excited for the next three months
because they're going to extrapolate
numbers into all of these. I don't think
those companies are ever going to get
them that way. I think there'll be some
nice stuff that comes. Maybe I'm wrong
on it, but I think this is going to be
the next hype cycle in terms of what
consumer agents are going to do. And I
think people are going to miss the fact
that this is more this is going to be a
better thing for the biology side than
the other side because I think this is a
research and science thing and not a
consumers are going to pay me more money
thing. I think in the end crypto is
going to benefit, but we'll get to that.
Research acceleration. Again, OpenAI
released this blog talking about how
fast it's going. Just look at the
internal use of coding agents and how
much that's changed lately. These are
parabolic moves in terms of what's
happening, how much they're using them.
It's just insane when you read the
numbers. And this is driving the price
of intelligence down faster than any
technology in history. So again, if
you're looking for productivity gains
and you go back to the Leopold, when you
reach the point of agents where now
10,000 agents can work together as
opposed to one human
using coding agents, now we're going to
have multi- agents working. That's why
you have to listen to the nome brown
thing and just start to get the numbers
because that's when you start to get
into the point that productivity
explodes. And this is why at this point
you want to be long speed and short
friction because everything that's
moving at human time and thinking at
human time think people worried about
rates is going to have a problem. You
cannot sit there and wait. You have to
be on top of what's happening. So if
you're someone managing money and you
are not fully in the know of compute of
agents and swarms of the crypto
guardrails and why they matter from the
financial side, I don't think you can
compete. I really don't. You're going to
be competing first of all with
computers, but if you're going to try to
find ideas, which I think is going to be
impossible to do because of what I've
seen on the agentic side for retail and
how much they're using it, I think you
have to be short friction and I think
you have to start to identify where you
make money. So, putting a trade on for
short friction right now, I think
there's a bare market. Like I said,
there's a bare market with inside a bull
market. Go short. If you're if you think
rates are going to blow something up, go
short housing. Go short the private
credit names. Go short the private
equity names that are still trading
down. Blue Al was down again this week
approaching low. Like find the things
that are clearly weak and go short
those. I just think you're making a big
mistake. This isn't the great financial
crisis. This isn't the time before where
everything was very sensitive to rates
because we hadn't had the iPhone yet.
The iPhone changed everything in 2007.
That is when the debt markets changed
forever and the market cap for the
equity market changed. Those are not
rate sensitive names. So again, AI plus
tokenization.
It's going to increase the speed
significantly because the agents will
now be doing the transactions. The
velocity of money is going to explode.
And like I said, M2, which right now
you're going to have a dramatic change
when wealth becomes part of M2 because
of speed.
I I just had to put this in there
because it was a deadcat bounce on
August 21st and my thematic my index is
up 42% since he sent that out. So, he's
he's really got a good track record uh
lately. Um if you're looking to catch up
on tokenization, I would start with Vlad
Tennv's Rob from Robin Hood. Uh he was
on moonshots this week. It's important
to listen to someone and think, can
someone at Morgan, Stanley, Goldman
Sachs, Bank of America, JP Morgan, go
through the list, can they compete with
a guy who understands AI so well? Could
anybody be on here on this show and talk
about the things that he talks about on
there? You have to listen to it and just
understand the advantage of being a
younger person in a world of AI with
agents. It's really a big deal to
understand that. And so to understand
the tokenization side to understand uh
Robin Hood chain these are all things
that it talks about self- custody is a
big deal he goes through that I think
all of these things are super important
as a thematic basis you don't have to
listen to the whole thing but I
definitely think when he says
tokenization will take over the entire
financial system and you're seeing that
happening where it's moving that
direction it should be there I highly
recommend that you read this I publishes
it as a substack for the exact reason
that even though This is going out to
subscribers
and all of my crypto stuff. Well, and
all of my stuff is basically going to be
behind the payw wall now. Um, not the
Substack and not the YouTube, but I want
to make sure that people understand that
I fully believe that this is the major
story and that you have to go through
it. And yes, I do take shots at people
in rates because we've fallen for this.
When you go through the things that we
fell for, I highlight them here. One
thing I want to remember is it was last
year we heard about Smoot Holly a
billion times and the Great Depression.
These fears continue relentlessly while
there's something bigger going on. Black
Rockck released the machine native
economy. How digital assets connect
intelligence, commerce, and compute.
They're going through a theme that I've
written about and talked about on this
for a long time. Pomp and I talked about
it this week that I've talked about this
for months, but they're finally starting
to focus the attention on machine native
transactions require purpose-built
agentic payment protocols. And that's
where we are. And that's why I've
highlighted to you guys Stripe. That's
why on the crypto video, I spent a lot
of time on Stripe. If you guys don't get
that and you're interested in it, it's
part of the overall AI package. So,
you're getting both of them together
because that was always the game plan is
that they both be on the payw wall. Um,
Black Rockck following that paper
middle of the week, it's taking model
portfolios on chain. So again, they will
tokenize through Ando Finance, part of
my 46 name basket, giving non- US non-
US 247 access via crypto wallets for
their portfolios.
Um, I'm telling you, for your children,
this is my focus. It's been an
entrepreneurs paradise and this is for
people of any age. The entrepreneurship
is blowing up because of AI. So there
are business creations happening at an
incredibly fast pace. And guess what?
Rates don't hurt them. Let me say that
again. Rates don't hurt them. These
companies don't need capital because
they're using AI. Remember that.
That's why this whole thing is in there
in terms of how the economics are going
to change on the back of
entrepreneurship. if you didn't get the
ghost rails piece. Again, we built the
crypto rails waiting for the app store
or for the people to move in. But the
mistake was that humans would never use
crypto. And that's a mistake that I
think everyone that believes in crypto
didn't recognize that in the end, you're
never going to change the people that
own the $900 trillion view on crypto.
I've seen it myself personally. They
don't want to take the time to learn
because they don't understand it and
they have no need to. They've already
made their money. If they would put some
money in, they might have some skin in
the game. Agents change that. They will
be the thing that changes it. Agents
will change it. And that's why AI agents
building the bridge is there. Here's the
video that I did. If you guys didn't see
it, it's an hour long. I promise you,
you will understand why now is time in
crypto. This is not happening for no
reason. So the same reason that I said
the MAG7 and all of the consumer agent
trade will be the trade and you're going
to get the stocks with the hype. Crypto
to me is at the beginning of a Peter
Lynch style bull market. For those of
you who have ever looked at Peter
Lynch's uh famous book back in the early
80s, his whole premise was that you
wanted to find something that the street
didn't cover that was in the early stage
and you had done the homework on it
before the masses did. That is the exact
definition of why now in crypto. It's
necessary because of AI agents. This is
the app store moment for crypto.
Whatever your views are of crypto,
remember stable coins, tokenization,
Bitcoin, Ethereum,
this all had to be built. And it took 15
years, 16 years. And guess what? The
internet to get to the app store took
about the exact same amount of time. And
that's when it took off. The.com bubble
was a representation of the ghost rails,
except for one thing. They used debt.
The crypto side went through its dot
bubble from VC money. Now we're in a
different stage. AI agents are coming.
The demand is picking up. And just like
token usage a year ago, the numbers will
explode in terms of agents consuming.
Are they going to start small? Sure.
But that's what Peter Lynch was looking
for. You by the time it's big, the trade
is up dramatically. Didn't you learn
your lesson with Micron?
So this was the first slide again. You
guys can go see it. And while breath is
bad in the stock market and you saw
where my names are on my Agentic
portfolio where there's now 60 some odd
above the
uh 50-day moving average
in my crypto 46 name tokenized index
which for you subscribers that didn't
see the video I did upload the index so
you can go see the names. It was up
another 3% today on Friday for the month
it's up 31%. Bitcoin's up 6 and a half.
Bitcoin is not what you watch right now.
You want to watch the index of which
Bitcoin is a member in it. 44 of 46
names are above the 50-day, 96%. The 200
day, 87%.
96% of the 50-day moving averages are
pointed upward and we are now to 72%.
This, my friends, is a bull market.
That's what the chart looks like. You
don't want to be part of this. And
remember, what did rates do?
Rates went higher. Well, isn't crypto
supposed to be very liquidity sensitive,
rate sensitive? H, maybe it's a bull
market. For more, for those of you who
haven't subscribed, who haven't reached
out, go have a conversation with Mark
Whailing. Mark's a good dude. You'll
have a fun time no matter what. Uh, but
you can go find him there. The Thai
terminal. For those of you who are
looking to start using something for
what you can go through like Bloomberg,
this would be my suggestion. Here are my
names. Look at this. Free six names for
you guys that are in there. Uh, and look
at the returns for the last seven days.
These are all part I uploaded these in
there. I'm just saying this is like
Bloomberg. You have charting functions,
you have news, you have all kinds of
fundamentals. These guys have done a
great job. Uh, I'll be speaking at their
event on October 27th. I would go sign
up if for no other reason. It's
institutions. It's they have a lot of
customers that are hedge funds, a lot of
customers that are mutual funds. It's
everything. This is not just crypto. I
think at some point, and again, there's
probably reason why they have it called
the bridge. And I'm showing you guys a
bridge on this. I think they're all
related. Uh again, Muse,
Coinbase, want to trade with Coinbase on
Muse? You can trade Coinbase on Muse.
Again, Muse just came out. You can do
all this stuff. That just shows the
rails are already set up. says crypto
and stable coins will be the go-to
payment method for agents. New York
Stock Exchange teams up with
blockchain.com to for tokeniz. This is
all this week, guys. Uh Robin Hood said
something big is coming in stock tokens
soon. And remember, they kind of are
involved with the government on this
stuff. The tokenization's happening.
Okay, so this is the part where I give
you a little bit of what I showed to the
subscribers.
I would go watch this immediately. And
again, I will have all of the um
podcasts for the subscribers that you
can go watch. I'll I gave you all the
info that'll come out an email at 9:00
on Sunday. Um Ali Yaya is a must listen
to. I don't he's not out there that
much. He's been a general partner at
Andre and Horowitz. This particular
episode on Unchanged on their five fund.
I just want to give you the highlights
of him and why it's important. So he's
been at A16Z since the beginning. He's a
former Google brain engineer, former
Google X researcher. He left while he
was with Google X because they would not
listen to him for an investment in
crypto. That was a long time ago.
But I want you to think about it. Here's
someone who is basically got a, you
know, his he specialized in computer uh
security, distributed systems,
networking, cryptography. He believed
this was going to be so big a long time
ago when they set up A16Z that he went
there. So when you listen to him speak,
he is someone that understands the
connection between AI and crypto. That's
why I'm directing you towards him. He is
very very good at kind of going through
it and he talks about how AI is
fundamentally different from where it's
headed. It's primarily a tool that
humans use. The next stage is what he
calls AI agents becoming autonomous
economic actors. So, if you want to go
through and understand why this is and
why it's so important, trust me, you
want to know what he's saying and you
want to go back to Mark Andre's paper of
why Bitcoin matters and just understand
that 12 years later, the story that he's
saying, Aliya, is what Mark said. Mark
didn't know stable coins would be part
of it. He didn't know tokenization would
be part of it. He didn't know Ethereum
would be so important. He was talking
about why Bitcoin matters. The ecosystem
has changed.
and it has gone into this. He didn't
know that AI agents would be here.
Nobody talked about autonomous agents in
this side. This is why it's such a big
deal
another video and actually the number
one one to listen to because this has
Chris Dixs and it has a bunch of
partners at A16Z along with Ali Yayya.
If you guys want to get up to speed on
this and you want to start to learn, I'm
not going to take you through all of
this, but they say AI dramatically
lowers the barrier to using programmable
money. That is critical. Again, humans
were never going to be able to do this.
AI agents are the major new catalyst for
crypto. They go through this whole
thing. This is from May. So, I want you
to go listen to this and realize that
they were right. I want you to go listen
and understand what's going to happen.
Agents could aggressively
disintermediate existing payment and
subscription models. Unlike humans,
agents have no attachment to Visa,
credit cards, brands, subscriptions, or
familiar interfaces.
Think about what the consumer side is.
Agents don't care about preferences.
They have no attachment.
You have to change your mind. For those
of you arguing with me on this, at least
look at it and go through. I don't care
about the other side of this. The other
side is everyone already uses Visa and
Mastercard. If agents are going to
disrupt,
this is very, very important. And I
listen to a lot of people tell me,
"Consumers want to walk into the mall.
They're never going to buy Amazon." And
don't tell me that that wasn't a story
that you didn't hear repeatedly, which
is the reason I went to Silicon Valley
in 2013, which was the how can Amazon
trade here? I don't get it. More
disclosures. Again, guys, it's been a
pleasure. Uh again, thanks to all the
people down in DC. I will be at uh the
Bitcoin Treasury Conference on Monday.
So, those of you that are there, come
by, see me. Uh I will be at Pomp's event
in uh two weeks and like I said, I'll be
at the bridge event and it seems like
I'm getting invited to a lot more. Uh
I'll see you guys next week. Thanks.